Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (rugs-woodworking)
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (rugs-woodworking)
1900-2005
VRC 6.4
Yale University Arts Library
12.08
29 boxes (Boxes 144-172 of 172)
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by medium. Principal categories include ceramics, furniture, glass, illuminated manuscripts, and silverware. Further arranged by chronological period, country, or region. Individual artists listed, if known.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Decorative arts; Photographs; Reproductions
- Rugs., 62 (Box 144)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 144)
  - Armenia., 1 (Box 144)
  - Persia., 53 (Box 144)
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 144)
    - XVI Century., 10 (Box 144)
    - XVII Century., 28 (Box 144)
    - XIX Century., 8 (Box 144)
    - XX Century., 1 (Box 144)
  - Turkey., 6 (Box 144)
- Silverware., 446 (Box 145)
  - Britain., 84 (Box 145)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 145)
    - XVII Century., 9 (Box 145)
      - Unknown artists., 7 (Box 145)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 145)
        - Cabrier, Charles., 1 (Box 145)
        - Nelme, Anthony., 1 (Box 145)
    - XVIII Century., 62 (Box 145)
      - Unknown artists., 24 (Box 145)
      - Known artists., 38 (Box 145)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 11 (Box 145)
          - Courtauld, Louisa and Samuel., 1 (Box 145)
          - Heming, Thomas., 1 (Box 145)
          - J. S., probably John Stoyte., 1 (Box 145)
          - Newton, John., 1 (Box 145)
          - Platel, Pierre., 1 (Box 145)
          - Richardson, Richard., 1 (Box 145)
          - Smith & Sharp of London, and Tuite, John., 1 (Box 145)
          - Sprimont, Nicholas., 1 (Box 145)
          - Storr, Paul, active 1792-1830s., 2 (Box 145)
            See also entry in XIX Century.
          - Wilhaume, David., 1 (Box 145)
        - Individual artists., 27 (Box 145)
          - Lamerie, Paul de., 27 (Box 145)
    - XIX Century., 10 (Box 146)
      - Known artists., 10 (Box 146)
        - A. M., 1 (Box 146)
        - Angell, Joseph., 1 (Box 146)
        - Ashbee, Charles Robert, 1863-1942., 1 (Box 146)
        - Creswick, T. and J., 1 (Box 146)
        - Emes, John., 1 (Box 146)
        - Hennell, R. and S., 1 (Box 146)
        - Richards & Brown., 1 (Box 146)
        - Smith, Benjamin., 1 (Box 146)
        - Storr, Paul, active 1792-1830s., 2 (Box 146)
          See also entry in XVIII Century.
  - Denmark., 1 (Box 146)
    - Known artists., 1 (Box 146)
      - Georg Jensen, XX C., 1 (Box 146)
  - France., 9 (Box 146)
    - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 146)
      - Unknown artists., 4 (Box 146)
      - Known artists., 3 (Box 146)
        - Beghin, Jean Francois, XVIII C., 1 (Box 146)
        - Rottiers de la Tour, Jacques-Nicolas, c.1736-1784., 1 (Box 146)
        - Samson, Louis II, 1710-1781., 1 (Box 146)
    - XX Century., 2 (Box 146)
  - Germany., 2 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 146)
    - Known artists., 1 (Box 146)
      - Brandt, Marianne, XX C., 1 (Box 146)
  - Holland., 3 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 3 (Box 146)
  - Italy., 3 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 146)
    - Known artists., 2 (Box 146)
      - Bella, Stefano della, 1610-1664., 1 (Box 146)
      - Ravasco, Alfredo, XX C., 1 (Box 146)
  - Norway., 2 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 146)
  - Russia. (Box 146)
  - Spain., 2 (Box 146)
    - Known artists., 2 (Box 146)
      - Lopex, Antonio, XVIII C., 1 (Box 146)
      - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 1 (Box 146)
  - Sweden., 4 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 146)
    - Known artists., 2 (Box 146)
      - Naukler, Henning, ?., 2 (Box 146)
  - United States., 336 (Box 146)
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 146)
    - Unknown artists., 40 (Box 146)
      - XVII Century., 10 (Box 146)
      - XVIII Century., 10 (Box 146)
      - XIX Century., 16 (Box 147)
      - XX Century., 4 (Box 147)
    - Known artists., 290 (Box 147)
    - A, B, C., 66 (Box 147)
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 28 (Box 147)
    - Allen, John, 1671-1760., 2 (Box 147)
      One work done with Edwards, 1670-1746.
    - Anderson, William, ?., 1 (Box 147)
    - Austin, Josiah, 1718-1780., 1 (Box 147)
    - Ball, Webb C., XIX C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Bassett, John, XVIII C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Bogard, Everard, XVII., 1 (Box 147)
    - Bogert, Nicholas J., XVIII- XIX C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Brasher, Ephraim, XVIII C., 2 (Box 147)
    - Brevoort, John, 1715-1775., 1 (Box 147)
    - Brigden, Zackariah, 1734-1787., 2 (Box 147)
    - Burt, John, 1691-1745., 3 (Box 147)
    - Burton, John S., ?., 1 (Box 147)
    - Casey, Samuel., XVIII C., 2 (Box 147)
    - Christensen, Hans, XX C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Churchill, Jesse, ?., 1 (Box 147)
    - Clark, I., XVIII C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Cluff, Matthew, XIX C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Coddington, John, 1690-1743., 3 (Box 147)
    - Coldwell, George., XVIII- XIX C., 1 (Box 147)
    - Cowell, William, 1682-1736., 1 (Box 147)
    - Individual Artists., 38 (Box 147)
    - Boelen, Jacob, 1654-1729., 5 (Box 147)
    - Burt, Benjamin, 1729-1805., 7 (Box 147)
    - Coney, John, 1655-1722., 26 (Box 147)
    - D, E, F, G, H., 73 (Box 148)
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 29 (Box 148)
    - Dane, Thomas, 1723-1796., 1 (Box 148)
    - David, John, 1680-1725., 2 (Box 148)
    - David, Peter, 1707-1735., 1 (Box 148)
    - Dolbeare, John, c.1664-1740., 1 (Box 148)
    - Fletcer & Gardiner, XIX C., 1 (Box 148)
    - Dubois, Abraham, active 1777-1804., 2 (Box 148)
    - Dunn, Cary, ?., 1 (Box 148)
    - Dupuy, Daniel, 1719-1807., 1 (Box 148)
    - Forbes, W.G., 1773-1803., 3 (Box 148)
    - Foster, Joseph, 1760-1839., 1 (Box 148)
    - Gale, William and Son, c.1823-1850., 2 (Box 148)
    - Garrett, Philip, 1780-1851., 1 (Box 148)
    - Graves, Michael, XX C., 1 (Box 148)
    - Grignon, Rene, active 1690-1715., 1 (Box 148)
    - Hall &Cotton, XIX C., 1 (Box 148)
    - Heyne, Johann Christoph, XVIII C., 4 (Box 148)
    - Hiller, Benjamin, 1688-1745., 1 (Box 148)
    - Humphreys, Richard, XVIII C., 1 (Box 148)
    - Hurd, Nathaniel, 1730-1777., 2 (Box 148)
    - Hutton, Isaac, XIX C., 3 (Box 148)
    - Individual Artists., 44 (Box 148)
    - Dixwell, John, 1680-1725., 4 (Box 148)
    - Dummer, Jeremiah, 1645-1718., 11 (Box 148)
    - Edwards, John, 1687-1743., 6 (Box 148)
    - Gorham &Co., 11 (Box 148)
    - Hurd, Jacob, 1702-1758., 12 (Box 148)
    - I, J, K, L, M., 28 (Box 149)
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 28 (Box 149)
    - I. B., XVII C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Inc, John, XVIII C., 1 (Box 149)
    - International Silver Co., XX C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Johnson, Samuel, XVIII C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Kierstede, Cornelius, 1675-1757., 3 (Box 149)
    - Le Roux, Bartholomew, -1713., 2 (Box 149)
    - Le Roux, Charles, 1689-1745., 2 (Box 149)
    - Lewis, Harvey, XIX C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Lobel, Paul, 1899-1983., 1 (Box 149)
    - Loring, Joseph, 1743-1815., 3 (Box 149)
    - Lupp, Henry, 1760-1800., 1 (Box 149)
    - Lupp, John, 1734-1805., 1 (Box 149)
    - McMullin, john, 1765-1843., 2 (Box 149)
    - Meriden Britannia Co., XIX C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Minott, Samuel, 1732-1803., 1 (Box 149)
    - Moulinar, John, 1744-1761., 1 (Box 149)
    - Myers, Myer, 1723-1795., 3 (Box 149)
    - Noyes, 1674-1749., 1 (Box 149)
    - Onkelbag, Garrett, 1670-1733., 1 (Box 149)
    - P, Q, R, S., 73 (Box 149)
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 24 (Box 149)
    - Pelletreau, Elaias, 1726-1810., 1 (Box 149)
    - Potwine, John, 1698-1792., 4 (Box 149)
    - Payne, Benjamin, 1684-1724., 1 (Box 149)
    - Reed and Barton, XIX C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Richards, Samuel and Williamson, Samuel, XVIII C., 3 (Box 149)
    - Ridout, George, XVIII C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1715-1769., 1 (Box 149)
    - Rouse, William, 1639-1704., 1 (Box 149)
    - Sanderson, Benjamin, 1649-1678., 1 (Box 149)
    - Schaats, Bartholomew, 1670-1758., 2 (Box 149)
    - Starr, Theodore B., active 1890-1900., 1 (Box 149)
    - Stone, Arthur J., ?., 2 (Box 149)
    - Stone Associates, XX C., 1 (Box 149)
    - Syng, Philip, 1703-1789., 3 (Box 149)
    - Van Dyck, Richard, 1717-1770., 1 (Box 149)
    - Individual Artists., 49 (Box 149)
    - Revere, Paul, 1735-1818., 25 (Box 149)
    - Richardson, Joseph Jr., XVIII C., 7 (Box 149)
    - Sanderson, Robert, 1608-1693., 11 (Box 150)
    - Soumain, Simeon, 1685-1750., 6 (Box 150)
    - T, u, V, W, X, Y, Z., 50 (Box 150)
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 14 (Box 150)
    - Turner, James, -1759., 1 (Box 150)
    - Unger Brothers, XX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Van Dyck, Richard, 1717-1770., 1 (Box 150)
    - Van Voorhis, Daniel, XVIII C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Walkins, Mildres, XX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Webb, Edward, 1690-1719., 1 (Box 150)
    - Whiting Mfg. Co., XIX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Whitmore, J., XVIII C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Wilm, H. I., XX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Wynkoop, Benjamin, 1675-1751., 2 (Box 150)
    - Wyncoop, Cornelius, 1701-., 1 (Box 150)
    - Wyon, E. XIX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Individual Artists., 36 (Box 150)
    - Tiffany &Co., XIX-XX C., 4 (Box 150)
    - Van der Burgh, Cornelius, 1653-1699., 5 (Box 150)
      name also spelled "Van der Burch".
    - Van der Spiegel, Jacobus, 1668-1708., 4 (Box 150)
    - Van Dyke, Peter, 1684-1750., 13 (Box 150)
    - Wislow, Edward, 1669-1753., 10 (Box 150)
    - Stage Design., 11 (Box 150)
    - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 150)
    - Known artists., 10 (Box 150)
    - Atchley, Whitney, XX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Hockney, David, 1937-., 1 (Box 150)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 1 (Box 150)
    - McConnell, Frederick, XX C., 1 (Box 150)
    - Salle, David, 1952-., 1 (Box 150)
    - Schinkel, Karl F., 1781-1841., 5 (Box 150)
- Stained Glass., 400 (Box 151)
  - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 151)
  - Britain., 33 (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 151)
    - XII Century., 5 (Box 151)
    - XIII Century., 4 (Box 151)
    - XIV to XV Century., 9 (Box 151)
    - XIX to XX Century., 12 (Box 151)
      - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 151)
      - Known artists., 10 (Box 151)
        - Burne-Jones, Edward, 1833-1898., 4 (Box 151)
        - Heaton, Butler & Bayne, XIX C., 1 (Box 151)
        - Kennedy, Hugh A., XIX C., 1 (Box 151)
        - Mackintosh, Charles Rennie, 1868-1928., 1 (Box 151)
        - Morris, William, 1834-1896., 1 (Box 151)
        - Piper, John, XX C., 1 (Box 151)
        - Wooldridge, Harry Ellis, 1845-1917., 1 (Box 151)
        - Yarington, Samuel Carter, 1781-1856., 1 (Box 151)
  - Flanders., 4 (Box 151)
    - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 151)
    - Known artists., 2 (Box 151)
      - Orley, Bernard van, 1492-1542., 1 (Box 151)
      - Vellert, Dirk Jacobs, XVI C., 1 (Box 151)
  - France., 223 (Box 152)
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 152)
    - XII Century., 47 (Box 152)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 16 (Box 152)
      - Chartres., 25 (Box 152)
      - S. Denis., 6 (Box 152)
    - XIII Century., 115 (Box 153)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 10 (Box 153)
      - Bourges., 8 (Box 153)
      - Chartres., 73 (Box 154)
      - Paris., 10 (Box 155)
      - Poitiers., 11 (Box 155)
        Some of the Poitiers works are from the XII C.
      - Rheims., 3 (Box 155)
    - XIV to XVI Century., 34 (Box 155)
      Includes a folder of miscellaneous locations.
      - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 155)
      - Tours., 19 (Box 155)
    - XX Century., 25 (Box 155)
      - Known artists., 25 (Box 155)
        - Barillet, Jean., 1 (Box 155)
        - Barillet, Louis., 1 (Box 155)
        - Bazin, Jean., 1 (Box 155)
        - Bony, Paul., 1 (Box 155)
        - Decorchemont, F., 3 (Box 155)
        - Gaudin, J., 1 (Box 155)
        - Gruber, Jacques., 1 (Box 155)
        - Hebert-Stevens, J., 3 (Box 155)
        - Labouret, Pierre., 2 (Box 155)
        - Le Chevalier, Jacques., 1 (Box 155)
        - Manessier, Alfred., 3 (Box 155)
        - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 1 (Box 155)
        - Reyre, Valentine., 1 (Box 155)
        - Rouault, Georges, 1871-1958., 3 (Box 155)
        - Varengeville, Chapel., 1 (Box 155)
        - Villon, Jacques, 1875-1963., 1 (Box 155)
  - Germany., 41 (Box 156)
    - X to XIII Century., 14 (Box 156)
    - XIV to XV Century., 15 (Box 156)
    - XVI Century., 9 (Box 156)
    - XX Century., 3 (Box 156)
      - Hindorf, Heinz, 1909-., 2 (Box 156)
      - Kleint, Boris., 1 (Box 156)
  - Holland., 13 (Box 156)
    - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 156)
    - Known artists., 8 (Box 156)
      - Crabeth, Dirck, active 1560., 2 (Box 156)
      - Nicolas, Joep, 1897-., 5 (Box 156)
      - Thorn-Prikker, Johan, 1868-1932., 1 (Box 156)
  - Italy., 24 (Box 156)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 156)
    - XV Century., 20 (Box 156)
      - Known artists., 20 (Box 156)
        - Castagno, Andrea del 1390-1457., 4 (Box 156)
        - Donatello, 1386-1466., 2 (Box 156)
        - Foppa, Vincenzo, 1425/30-1515., 1 (Box 156)
        - Ghiberti, Lorenzo, 1378-1456., 3 (Box 156)
        - Ghirlandaio, Domenico, 1449-1494., 4 (Box 156)
        - Uccello, Paolo, 1396-1475., 6 (Box 156)
  - Russia., 13 (Box 157)
    - Known artists., 13 (Box 157)
      - Chagall, Marc, 1887-1985., 13 (Box 157)
  - Spain., 1 (Box 157)
  - Switzerland., 3 (Box 157)
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 157)
    - Known artists., 1 (Box 157)
      - Murer, Josias, XVI-XVII C., 1 (Box 157)
  - United States., 43 (Box 157)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 157)
    - Known artists., 39 (Box 157)
      - Ascenzo Studio, XX C., 3 (Box 157)
      - Albers, Josef, 1888-1976., 3 (Box 157)
      - Bolton, William Jay, 1816-1884., 1 (Box 157)
      - Burnham, Wilbur Herbert, 1887-., 2 (Box 157)
      - Connick, Charles J., 1875-., 2 (Box 157)
      - Girard, Andre, XX C., 1 (Box 157)
      - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1903-1974., 1 (Box 157)
      - La Farge, John, 1835-1910., 5 (Box 157)
      - Obermayr, Terry, 1926-., 1 (Box 157)
      - Tiffany, Louis Comfort, 1848-1933, and studio., 11 (Box 157)
        See also: Glass, United States.
      - Willet, William and Annie Lee, XX C., 1 (Box 157)
      - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959., 8 (Box 157)
- Tapestry., 419 (Box 158)
  - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 158)
  - Early Christian (Coptic)., 21 (Box 158)
  - Belgium., 6 (Box 158)
    - Brussels Workshops., 4 (Box 158)
    - Van der Borght, Peter, 1712-1763., 2 (Box 158)
  - Britain., 22 (Box 158)
    - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 158)
    - Known artists., 11 (Box 158)
      - Burne-Jones, Edward, 1833-1898., 8 (Box 158)
      - Sutherland, Graham, 1903-1980., 1 (Box 158)
      - Vanderbank, John, 1694-1739., 2 (Box 158)
  - Flanders., 64 (Box 159)
    Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings and a portfolio of numerous prints.
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 159)
    - XVI Century., 58 (Box 159)
      - Miscellaneous works., 36 (Box 159)
      - Known artists., 22 (Box 159)
        - Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640., 2 (Box 159)
        - Van Aelst, Pieter., 1 (Box 159)
        - Van Orley, Bernard, 1485/93-1542., 19 (Box 159)
  - France., 227 (Box 160)
    - XI Century., 22 (Box 160)
      - Bayeux Tapestry., 22 (Box 160)
    - XIV Century., 15 (Box 160)
    - XV Century., 91 (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous works., 54 (Box 161-, Box 162)
      - Unicorn Tapestries., 37 (Box 162)
    - XVI Century., 35 (Box 163)
      - Miscellaneous works., 30 (Box 163)
      - Cousin, Jean., 5 (Box 163)
    - XVII Century., 21 (Box 163)
      - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 163)
      - Gobelins., 15 (Box 163)
    - XVIII Century., 25 (Box 164)
      - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 164)
      - Gobelins., 15 (Box 164)
    - XIX Century., 1 (Box 164)
    - XX Century., 16 (Box 164)
      - Known artists., 16 (Box 164)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 11 (Box 164)
          - Braques, George, 1882-., 1 (Box 164)
          - Dufy, Raoul, 1880-., 2 (Box 164)
          - Gromaire, Marcel., 2 (Box 164)
          - Guignebert, J.- C., 1 (Box 164)
          - Leger, Fernand, 1881-1955., 1 (Box 164)
          - Rouault, Georges, 1871-., 1 (Box 164)
          - Saint-Saens, Marc., 2 (Box 164)
          - Vera, Paul, 1882-., 1 (Box 164)
        - Individual artists., 5 (Box 164)
          - Lurcat, Jean, 1892-., 5 (Box 164)
  - Germany., 21 (Box 165)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 165)
    - XII to XIV Century., 9 (Box 165)
    - XV to XVI Century., 9 (Box 165)
  - Iceland., 1 (Box 165)
  - Italy., 24 (Box 165)
    - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 165)
    - Works after Raphael., 12 (Box 165)
  - Norway., 11 (Box 165)
  - Spain., 14 (Box 165)
    - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 165)
    - Known artists., 2 (Box 165)
      - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 2 (Box 165)
  - United States., 3 (Box 165)
- Textiles., 318 (Box 166)
  Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 166)
  - Islamic., 57 (Box 166)
    - Persia., 47 (Box 166)
      - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 166)
      - IV to VIII Century (Sassanian)., 7 (Box 166)
      - XVI Century., 9 (Box 166)
      - XVII Century., 13 (Box 166)
      - XVIII Century., 5 (Box 166)
    - Turkey., 10 (Box 167)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 167)
      - XVI Century., 8 (Box 167)
      - XVII Century., 1 (Box 167)
  - Early Christian., 40 (Box 167)
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 167)
    - Coptic., 34 (Box 167)
  - Byzantine., 9 (Box 167)
  - Post-Romanesque., 202 (Box 168)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 168)
    - Austria., 5 (Box 168)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 168)
      - Known artists., 4 (Box 168)
        - Hoffmann, Josef, 1870-1918., 1 (Box 168)
        - Schiele, Egon, 1890-1918., 1 (Box 168)
        - Wiener Werkstatte, XX C., 2 (Box 168)
    - Britain., 35 (Box 168)
      - Miscellaneous works., 32 (Box 168)
      - Known artists., 3 (Box 168)
        - Morris, William, 1834-1896, and Co., 2 (Box 168)
        - Stevens, Thomas, XIX C., 1 (Box 168)
    - Flanders., 1 (Box 168)
    - France., 13 (Box 168)
      - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 168)
      - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 2 (Box 168)
    - Germany., 27 (Box 168)
      - Miscellaneous works., 25 (Box 168)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 168)
        - Arp, Hans, 1888-., 1 (Box 168)
        - Obrist, Hermann, 1863-1927., 1 (Box 168)
    - Italy., 30 (Box 169)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 169)
      - XIV Century., 4 (Box 169)
      - XV Century., 12 (Box 169)
      - XVI Century., 2 (Box 169)
      - XVII to XVIII Century., 8 (Box 169)
      - XX Century., 1 (Box 169)
    - Russia., 5 (Box 169)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 169)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 169)
        - Delaunay, Sonia, 1885-1979., 2 (Box 169)
    - Spain., 7 (Box 169)
    - Mexico., 1 (Box 169)
    - Peru (Colonial)., 7 (Box 169)
    - United States., 68 (Box 170)
      - Miscellaneous works., 33 (Box 170)
      - Quilts., 24 (Box 170)
      - Samplers., 11 (Box 170)
- Wallpaper., 6 (Box 171)
- Woodcarving., 28 (Box 171)
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 171)
  - France., 3 (Box 171)
  - Germany., 12 (Box 171)
  - Greenland., 1 (Box 171)
  - Holland., 1 (Box 171)
  - Italy., 5 (Box 171)
  - Netherlands., 1 (Box 171)
  - Spain., 1 (Box 171)
  - United States., 3 (Box 171)
- Miscellaneous., 84 (Box 172)
  Includes a folder of Cartouches, a folder of children's art, a folder of scale drawings, afolder of art cartoons, and a folder of really miscellaneous.
  - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 172)
  - Color., 11 (Box 172)
  - Movements., 25 (Box 172)
    - AIDS., 3 (Box 172)
    - Art Deco., 8 (Box 172)
    - Art Nouveau., 6 (Box 172)
    - Bauhaus., 2 (Box 172)
    - Cubism., 1 (Box 172)
    - Dada., 3 (Box 172)
    - Expressionism., 1 (Box 172)
    - Pop Art., 1 (Box 172)
  - Perspective., 5 (Box 172)
  - Portraits., 4 (Box 172)
    - Transportation., 29 (Box 172)